Mahdi Moeini

100 Terra Nova Rd, St. John's, Newfoundland, Canada, A1B1G2

+1 (709) 699-9147 | mmoeini@mun.ca | www.linkedin.com/in/mmoeini | www.m-moeini.github.io

SUMMARY

An Energetic, hardworking Master Computer Engineering student interested in solving mathematical and algorithm challenges. Having two years of work experience in programming and a Bachelor's in Electrical Engineering, I intend to expand my theoretical and practical knowledge in a professional environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Backend Developer | Toranj Innovative Company | Tehran, Iran

May 2021–Feb 2022

- Collaborated backend team in developing and debugging **event-driven microservices** in **JAVA** language, which resulted in launching the Medx project as a web platform for health insurance companies to process their financial tasks.
- Coded Acceptance Tests REST APIs and connected them to the FitNesse framework
- Shared information on **Scrum** sessions to evaluate and improve the projects
- Developed a small online shop named <u>Sheipoor</u> as a testing task in **monolithic** and **Microservice** architecture in **MVC** with **Spring boot**, **Spring security**, and **JPA**

Embedded Systems Developer | Hoom Company | Tehran, Iran

June 2020–Nov 2020

- Team-worked on IoT protocols such as MQTT and BLE and implemented them on ARM microcontrollers in C and C++ languages, which led to the development of a smart door locker controlled by Bluetooth through an online software
- Designed and coded <u>IoT Gateway</u>, taking client commands with BLE and sending them to the server with MQTT to manage multiple connections to the smart devices
- Researched and gathered information on new IoT technologies for designing new IoT devices

Teaching Assistant of Electronics I | Instructor: Dr. Adib Abrishamifar

Feb 2021-July 2021

Iran University of Science and Technology

- Taught PSPICE
- Designed and marked the course projects
- Provided instructing materials for the course

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Engineering

Sept 2022–Sept 2024 (Expected)

Memorial University of Newfoundland (GPA: 9.05/10)

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering

Sept 2017-Feb 2022

Iran University of Science and Technology (GPA: 8.09/10)

SKILLS

- Programming languages: Proficient in JAVA, C, C++, and Sufficient knowledge of Python and JS
- Technologies: Good knowledge of Spring, JPA, Hibernates, JSP, Maven, and MySQL
- Terminologies: Proficient in OOP, familiar with Agile and CI/CD principles
- Architecture and Design patterns: Capable of Coding in MVC and Monolithic Architecture, familiar with Microservices, Clean Architecture, and Event-Driven Architecture
- Soft Skills: Teamwork ability, solid skills of concentration and observation, Strong presentation ability, Proficiency in English, and actively learning French